Out of the sky comes the screen's most incredible spectacle of men and war!
A Bridge Too Far is a drama, history, war film directed by Richard Attenborough.
The story of Operation Market Garden—a failed attempt by the allies in the latter stages of WWII to end the
war quickly by securing three bridges in Holland allowing access over the Rhine into Germany.
A combination of poor allied intelligence and the presence of two crack German panzer divisions meant that
the final part of this operation (the bridge in Arnhem over the Rhine) was doomed to failure.
Lt. Gen. Frederick Browning, played by Dirk Bogarde.
SSgt. Eddie Dohun, played by James Caan.
Lt. Col. John O.E. Vandeleur, played by Michael Caine.
Maj. Gen. Robert E. Urquhart, played by Sean Connery.
Lt. Gen. Brian G. Horrocks, played by Edward Fox.
Maj. Julian Cook, played by Robert Redford.
A Bridge Too Far is a 1977 epic war film directed by Richard Attenborough.
It depicts Operation Market Garden, a failed Allied operation in the Nazi-occupied Netherlands during World War II; the
film's screenplay, by William Goldman, is based on a book of the same title by historian Cornelius Ryan.
It stars an ensemble cast, featuring Dirk Bogarde, James Caan, Michael Caine, Sean Connery, Edward Fox, Elliott Gould, Gene
Hackman, Anthony Hopkins, Hardy Krüger, Laurence Olivier, Ryan O'Neal, Robert Redford, Maximilian Schell and Liv Ullmann.
Independently produced by Attenborough and Joseph E.
Levine, it was the second film based on a book by Ryan to be
adapted for the screen (after The Longest Day (1962)).
It was the second film based on the events of Operation Market
Garden, following Theirs Is the Glory (1946).
A co-production between the United Kingdom and the United States, the film was shot on location in
the Netherlands, in many of the real locations where the historical events took place.
Although released to a tepid critical response, A
Bridge Too Far received several awards.
At the 31st BAFTA Awards it won four out of eight nominated categories, including Best Supporting Actor for Edward Fox
and Best Score for John Addison—who himself had served in the British XXX Corps during Market Garden.
Attenborough was nominated for Best Direction, and the
film was nominated for Best Motion Picture.
It was a success at the box office, becoming the
sixth-most popular movie of 1977.
The film explores themes of mission, army, allies, world war ii, netherlands.
The tone is emotional.